{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","address":"15 E Kirby St","zipcode":"48207","owner":"Park Shelton Association ","licenseNumber":"061070","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"4/27/2018","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E6100000741613543AC454C0D870B9B0242E4540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44632","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2018-12-05T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"114","pcount":"1","pfcount":"2","ccount":"7","criticalcount":"3","noncritical":"7","correctedcritical":"3","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.112","violationDescription":"Dead or trapped birds, insects, rodents, and other pests shall be removed from control devices and the PREMISES at a frequency that prevents their accumulation,  decomposition, or the attraction of pests.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Dead/trapped pest(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not removed from facility","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove from facility/premises."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-05T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Datemark with a discard date of 7 days or less."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Single-service/single-use article(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without packaging/wrapping","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide packaging/wrapping."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not covered","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep covered."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"7-202.12","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS shall be:    \r\n(A) Used according to:      \r\n(1) LAW and this Code,   \r\n(2) Manufacturer's use directions included in labeling, and, for a pesticide, manufacturer's label instructions that state that use is allowed in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, (P)   \r\n(3) The conditions of certification, if certification is required, for use of the pest control materials, (P) and   \r\n(4) Additional conditions that may be established by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY; and\r\n(B) Applied so that:      \r\n(1) A HAZARD to EMPLOYEES or other PERSONS is not constituted, (P) and   \r\n(2) Contamination including toxic residues due to drip, drain, fog, splash or spray on FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES is prevented, and for a RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE, this is achieved by: (P)      \r\n(a) Removing the items, (P)   \r\n(b) Covering the items with impermeable covers, (P) or   \r\n(c) Taking other appropriate preventive actions, (P) and   \r\n(d) Cleaning and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS after the application. (P)  \r\n(C) A RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE shall be applied only by an applicator certified as defined in 7 USC 136 Definitions, (e) Certified Applicator, of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, or a PERSON under the direct supervision of a certified applicator. (Pf)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Applied in manor that contaminates food-contact surfaces","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-05T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Apply in manner that prevents contamination."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Ice machine","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\r\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Used for culinary purposes","subProblem":"Cleaning","location":"SUSHI BAR","subLocation":"Hand sink(s)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-05T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discontinue use of hand sink for this use and use appropriate sink."},{"inspectionid":"44632","inspectionDate":"12/5/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-802.11","violationDescription":"(A) LINENS that do not come in direct contact with FOOD shall be laundered between operations if they become wet, sticky, or visibly soiled.   \r\n(B) Cloth gloves used as specified in ¶ 3-304.15(D) shall be laundered before being used with a different type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork or POULTRY.   \r\n(C) LINENS and napkins that are used as specified under § 3-304.13 and cloth napkins shall be laundered between each use.   \r\n(D) Wet wiping cloths shall be laundered daily.   \r\n(E) Dry wiping cloths shall be laundered as necessary to prevent contamination of FOOD and clean serving UTENSILS.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Non-food contact linen(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not laundered when","subProblem":"Visibly soiled","location":"STAIRWAY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Launder to keep clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"43424","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2018-08-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inspectorid":"114","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"42437","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2018-05-10T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"114","pcount":"2","pfcount":"1","ccount":"5","criticalcount":"3","noncritical":"5","correctedcritical":"3","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-307.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination that may result from a factor or source not specified under Subparts 3-301 - 3-306.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not protected","subProblem":"From contamination","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Protect against contamination"},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"7-202.12","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS shall be:    \r\n(A) Used according to:      \r\n(1) LAW and this Code,   \r\n(2) Manufacturer's use directions included in labeling, and, for a pesticide, manufacturer's label instructions that state that use is allowed in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, (P)   \r\n(3) The conditions of certification, if certification is required, for use of the pest control materials, (P) and   \r\n(4) Additional conditions that may be established by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY; and\r\n(B) Applied so that:      \r\n(1) A HAZARD to EMPLOYEES or other PERSONS is not constituted, (P) and   \r\n(2) Contamination including toxic residues due to drip, drain, fog, splash or spray on FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES is prevented, and for a RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE, this is achieved by: (P)      \r\n(a) Removing the items, (P)   \r\n(b) Covering the items with impermeable covers, (P) or   \r\n(c) Taking other appropriate preventive actions, (P) and   \r\n(d) Cleaning and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS after the application. (P)  \r\n(C) A RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE shall be applied only by an applicator certified as defined in 7 USC 136 Definitions, (e) Certified Applicator, of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, or a PERSON under the direct supervision of a certified applicator. (Pf)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Applied in manor that contaminates food-contact surfaces","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Apply in manner that prevents contamination."},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-301.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT for cooling and heating FOOD, and holding cold and hot FOOD, shall be sufficient in number and capacity to provide FOOD temperatures as required. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"cold holding","problemDescription":"Inadequate","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-28T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide additional equipment to meet requirement above."},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"In standing water","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Food contact surfaces","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store as stated above."},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-602.12","violationDescription":"(A) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking and baking EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours. This section does not apply to hot oil cooking and filtering EQUIPMENT if it is cleaned as specified in Subparagraph 4-602.11(D)(6).   \r\n(B) The cavities and door seals of microwave ovens shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours by using the manufacturer's recommended cleaning procedure.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Microwave oven door seals and cavities","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Microwave Oven(s)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-13T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"inspectionid":"42437","inspectionDate":"5/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.18","violationDescription":"PLUMBING FIXTURES such as HANDWASHING SINKS, toilets, and urinals shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"sink","subItem":"handwash","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"Throughout","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-13T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"40514","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"127","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"40514","inspectionDate":"10/19/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"sanitizer","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Label containers with common name."},{"inspectionid":"40514","inspectionDate":"10/19/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"inspectionid":"40514","inspectionDate":"10/19/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above.e"}]},{"inspectionid":"38466","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2017-03-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"130","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"3","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"3","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"38466","inspectionDate":"3/22/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FLOOR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"38466","inspectionDate":"3/22/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-501.19","violationDescription":"The temperature of the wash solution in manual WAREWASHING EQUIPMENT shall be maintained at not less than 110 F or the temperature specified on the cleaning agent manufacturer's label instructions. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Manual warewash wash solution","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 110 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"THREE COMPARTMENT SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Change water frequently to maintain at least 110 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"38466","inspectionDate":"3/22/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.18","violationDescription":"PLUMBING FIXTURES such as HANDWASHING SINKS, toilets, and urinals shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"sink","subItem":"handwash","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"38466","inspectionDate":"3/22/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"THREE COMPARTMENT SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above.e"},{"inspectionid":"38466","inspectionDate":"3/22/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Failed to notify the health department that an employee is diagnosed with a \"big 4\" illness","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide"}]},{"inspectionid":"36362","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","inspectionDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"114","pcount":"2","pfcount":"3","ccount":"5","criticalcount":"5","noncritical":"5","correctedcritical":"5","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"2-302.11","violationDescription":"(A)     FOOD EMPLOYEES shall keep their fingernails trimmed, filed, and maintained so the edges and surfaces are cleanable and not rough. (Pf)\r\n(B)     Unless wearing intact gloves in good repair, a FOOD EMPLOYEE may not wear fingernail polish or artificial fingernails when working with exposed FOOD. (Pf)\r\n ","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Fingernails","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-30T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Trim, file and maintain."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"3-307.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination that may result from a factor or source not specified under Subparts 3-301 - 3-306.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not protected","subProblem":"From contamination","location":"CUTTING SURFACES","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Protect against contamination"},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-30T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"2-401.11","violationDescription":"(A)    An EMPLOYEE shall eat, drink, or use any form of tobacco only in designated areas where the contamination of exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES; or other items needing protection can not result.\r\n(B)     A FOOD EMPLOYEE may drink from a closed BEVERAGE container if the container is handled to prevent contamination of:\r\n         (1)     The EMPLOYEE'S hands;\r\n         (2)     The container; and\r\n         (3)     Exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Beverage container","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not covered","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Cover."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-501.18","violationDescription":"The wash, rinse, and SANITIZE solutions shall be maintained clean.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Warewashing solutions","subItem":"rinse","problemDescription":"Not clean","subProblem":"","location":"THREE COMPARTMENT SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean"},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-30T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\r\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Used for culinary purposes","subProblem":"Cleaning","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discontinue use of hand sink for this use and use appropriate sink."},{"inspectionid":"36362","inspectionDate":"9/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"3707","name":"Wasabi","violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"Inadequate Sanitizer bucket","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"3707"}}